Jumbo Club Records UA167
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Jumbo Club Records
1969 -- 2008
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Jumbo Club Inc.
Alumni Relations
Board of Overseers for Athletics
Athletics Department
UA167
3.7 Linear Feet 4 boxes
8 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Administrative files; Ephemera; and Photographs.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, agendas, meeting minutes, photographs, reports, and ephemera created by or pertaining to the Tufts Jumbo Club. Records were created between 1969, when the club was founded, until 2008, three years after the club officially disbanded. A large number of photographs document Jumbo Club events and athletics at Tufts from 1970 until 2005. A few items of ephemera, two banners, and five awards pins from around 2000 are also contained in the collection.
Related Materials
Jumbo Jottings, UP157, DCA
Biographical / Historical
Tufts Jumbo Club was an alumni organization founded in 1969 to provide financial support for Tufts athletic facilities and teams, and to provide recognition to members of Tufts' athletic community. At its peak, the Jumbo Club had over 1,000 dues-paying members, making it one of the largest alumni groups at Tufts. The Club was responsible for planning the annual Jumbo Club Awards banquet, a tradition that began in the spring of 1970. In addition to honoring Tufts athletes and coaches, the Jumbo Club also presented an annual Distinguished Achievement Award in coordination with Tufts Athletics Department, which recognized local athletic figures of note. Recipients included Nancy Kerrigan, Robert Kraft, and Joan Benoit Samuelson. Tufts Jumbo Club recorded notable happenings in their newsletter, Jumbo Jottings.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Alumni and Alumni Relations; Student Activities -- Athletics; Curriculum and Instruction -- Scholarships, Fellowships, Awards
- Administrative files, 1969 -- 2008; UA167.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The administrative files series is predominantly composed of the correspondence, agendas, board meeting minutes, and tax records of Tufts Jumbo Club, created between 1985 and 2004. This series also includes an early history of Tufts Jumbo Club from 1969 to 1975 compiled by Jumbo Club Historian, Francis Archibald. This provides a comprehensive background on the Club's founding, as well as documentation of early activities and events. There are also a number of letters and agendas pertaining to a 1992 football game between Tufts and Bowdoin that took place in Galway, Ireland. In addition this series includes a letter to the Jumbo Club from former president Bill Clinton, thanking the Club for honoring him as an award recipient at their 25th anniversary banquet in 1994.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1986 -- 1989; UA167.001.001.00001 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1979 -- 1986; UA167.001.001.00002 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 2000 -- 2004; UA167.001.001.00003 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1994 -- 2000; UA167.001.001.00004 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1991 -- 1994; UA167.001.001.00005 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1990 -- 1991; UA167.001.001.00006 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1989 -- 1990; UA167.001.001.00007 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1988 -- 1989; UA167.001.001.00008 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1990 -- 1998; UA167.001.001.00009 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 1999 -- 2000; UA167.001.001.00010 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Correspondence and Agendas, 2000 -- 2005; UA167.001.001.00011 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - [Jumbo Club taxes], 2001 -- 2002; UA167.001.001.00012 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Jumbo Club taxes, 02-03 Quigley, Raimo & co. PC, 2002 -- 2003; UA167.001.001.00013 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Jumbo Club taxes, 03-04 Goldfarb, Band & co. PC, 2003 -- 2004; UA167.001.001.00014 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Jumbo Club taxes, 04-05 Goldfarb, Band & co. PC, 2004 -- 2005; UA167.001.001.00015 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - [Jumbo Club taxes], 2006 -- 2008; UA167.001.001.00016 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Letter from Clinton, 1994; UA167.001.001.00017 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
    This folder contains a letter from President Bill Clinton thanking Tufts Jumbo Club for honoring him at their 25th Anniversary Awards Banquet.
  - Misc. Magazines, Pamphlets, and Newspaper Clippings, 1981 -- 1994; UA167.001.001.00018 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Football vs. Bowdoin. Galway, Ireland, 1992; UA167.001.001.00019 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Jumbo Club History (folder 1 of 2), 1969 -- 1975; UA167.001.001.00020 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Jumbo Club History (folder 2 of 2), 1969 -- 1975; UA167.001.001.00021 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
- Ephemera, 2000; UA167.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series includes two Jumbo Club banners displayed at Jumbo Club events between 2000 and 2005. It also contains five pins that were presented to Jumbo Club award recipients in approximately the same time frame.
  This series is arranged according to size and material.
  - [Jumbo Club Award pins], 2000; UA167.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
    This box contains five awards pins. Pin reads: "Tufts Jumbo Club Award" and depicts an elephant holding a Tufts banner in its tusk.
  - [Small banner with elephant insignia], 2000; UA167.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - [Large banner with elephant insignia], 2000; UA167.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
- Photographs, 1975 -- 2005; UA167.003; 2.2 Linear Feet; 7 Digital Object(s)
  This series includes photographs documenting the activities of the Jumbo Club, as well as Athletics at Tufts. A majority of the photographs depict events from 1990 to 2005, including awards banquets and dedications. There is also a large collection of photographs from the Athletics Department, which contain images of athletes, coaches, and games from 1970 until 2004. A number of older photographs show important figures in Tufts Athletics, including John Baronian, William Grinnel, and Rocco Carzo. Older historical photographs can also be found in the Jumbo Club History in Series 1.
  - Athletic Club, 1989 -- 2000; UA167.003.001.00022 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department [1 of 3], 1983 -- 1985; UA167.003.001.00023 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department [2 of 3], 1993 -- 1995; UA167.003.001.00024 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department [3 of 3], 1993 -- 1999; UA167.003.001.00025 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department: 25th Anniversary Women's Athletics, 1994; UA167.003.001.00026 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department: Christmas Party, 1992 -- 1997; UA167.003.001.00027 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department: Distinguished Achievement Award, John Hannah, Nancy Kerrigan, 1994; UA167.003.001.00028 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department: Distinguished Achievement Award, Jim Lonborg, Jackie McMullan, 1995; UA167.003.001.00029 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department: Distinguished Achievement Award, Johnny Pesky, Gino Cappelletti, 1996; UA167.003.001.00030 (Box UA167 Shared 1)
  - Athletic Department: Distinguished Achievement Award, Dan Duquette, Kristine Lilly, 50th Anniversary of Tufts Baseball World Series Team, 2000; UA167.003.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Athletic Department: Distinguished Achievement Award, Bill Richardson 2001, 2003 Jumbo Club Awards, Jumbo Club Special Projects, UA167.003.003.00002
    Richardson, Bill, 1947 Nov. 15-
    - Bill Richardson accepting 2001 Athletic Department Distinguished Achievement Award, UA167.003.003.00002.00001; Unknown
  - Athletic Department: Distinguished Achievement Award, Robert Kraft, 2003; UA167.003.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - [Athletic Department: Homecoming], 2000; UA167.003.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Athletic Department: Jeff Cicia retirement, 1997; UA167.003.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Athletic Department: Misc. events (staff parties, Goomba party, senior day), 1993 -- 1999; UA167.003.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Athletic Department: Student Athlete Awards, 1990; UA167.003.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Commencement Weekend, 2001; UA167.003.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Jumbo Club [1 of 3], 1990 -- 1995; UA167.003.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Jumbo Club [2 of 3], 1975 -- 1989; UA167.003.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Jumbo Club [3 of 3], 1979 -- 1999; UA167.003.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Jumbo Club 20th Anniversary, 1989; UA167.003.003.00012 (Box 3)
    Contains pictures of 20th Anniversary of Jumbo Club
    - Jumbo Club past presidents, 1989; UA167.003.003.00012.00001; Unknown (Box 3)
      Jumbo Club past presidents (left to right): Jeff Cicia, A '54, Bob Meehan, A '54, Dick Littlefield, A '51, Al Nardini, A '55, "Johnny" Grinnell, A '35, Dick Murphy, A '49, Eddie O'Connell, A '50, Jack Heneghan, A '55, John Baronian, A '50, Dick Lawrence, A '53, Ralph Goldstein, A '51, Tom Myers, A '54, Faith Ellis Heneghan, J '54, Bob Berluti, A '77, Bob Atkinson, A '56, and Tim Horgan, A '49.
      People; Anniversaries; photographic print; Meehan, Robert; Grinnell, William G. "Johnny"; O'Connell, Edward F.; Baronian, John; Goldstein, Dr. Ralph H.; Berluti, Bob; Horgan, Timothy; Jumbo Club
  - Jumbo Club 25th Anniversary, 1999; UA167.003.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Jumbo Club: Alumni Awards, 1999; UA167.003.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Jumbo Club: Jumbo Club Awards, 1996; UA167.003.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club: Jumbo Club Awards, 1999 -- 2002; UA167.003.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club: Jumbo Club Awards, 2003-04-04; UA167.003.004.00003
    Images by JD Sloan.
  - Jumbo Club: Jumbo Club Awards, 2004; UA167.003.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club: Jumbo Club Awards, 2005; UA167.003.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club Golf, 2000; UA167.003.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club: Niles Scoreboard Dedication, 1994; UA167.003.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club: Opening of Chase Gymnasium, 1996; UA167.003.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo Club: Scrapbook photos, 1988; UA167.003.004.00009 (Box 4)
    - Dignitaries at the Distinguished Achievement Award Banquet, 1988; UA167.003.004.00009.00001; Night Sparks Photography (Box 4)
      Left to right: Jumbo Club President Jeff Cicia, Baaron Pittenger, Joan Benoit Samuelson, Athletic Director Rocky Carzo, Bud Collins, Tim Horgan, 1st Vice President Dick Lawrence.
      People; Awards; photographic print; Carzo, Rocco "Rocky"; Horgan, Timothy
    - Jumbo Club Honorary Directors Johnny Grinnell and Jim Dodwell, 1988; UA167.003.004.00009.00002; Unknown (Box 4)
      Photo labeled: The first Jumbo Club Honorary Directors: (L.) "Johnny" Grinnell ('35) and Jim Dodwell ('39).
      Awards; photographic print; Grinnell, William G. "Johnny"; Dodwell, Jim; Jumbo Club